The battle is imminent.
Guo Zijian, let me tell you,
if it weren't for the Political Commissar,
I would strip you of your command.
Deputy Brigade Commander.
If I've hurt your pride,
I apologize.
But I hope you can
seriously consider my suggestion.
Fine.
Let me tell you,
you are not the Chief of Staff of the 396th Brigade,
nor are you a recon squad leader.
Your post
is in the 1st Battalion.
Get back to your post.
Yes, sir.
Guo Zijian
You stop right there!
Stop!
Deputy Brigade Commander Suo outranks you.
You need to watch your attitude.
Political Commissar.
Wars aren't fought with attitudes.
Even if wars aren't fought with attitudes,
but a bad attitude causes internal damage.
How you feel,
we all understand.
But the battle is about to start.
Are we to change the entire deployment?
There's no time for that.
Political Commissar.
In modern warfare, once a chance appears,
we can immediately use suppressive fire.
How could there not be enough time?
To tell you the truth,
you never intended to fight a real battle.
Guo Zijian!
What kind of talk is that?
Am I wrong?
This exercise is a great opportunity,
but all you leaders have in your heads are
exercise directives,
grading standards and exercise rules.
No wonder Deputy Brigade Commander fumed.
What are you saying?
The truth.
You're fighting a battle for scores,
for spreadsheets.
It's not a life-and-death battle.
Guo Zijian!
Sorry, Political Commissar. I was rash.
Guo Zijian.
At the academy, you were always engaged in
combat research.
Force-on-force exercises must have rules,
Is it wrong to have rules?
Political Commissar.
Having rules isn't wrong.
But relying solely on those rules
that is wrong.
Fine, let me ask you.
Even if we adjust our combat deployment,
we still need a target, right?
You said their command post is fake.
Then where is the real one?
Captain Zeng,
do me a favor.
What do you mean?
Didn't you say to let the data speak?
This location
is both hidden and remote.
Based on all the data,
it perfectly matches
the Blue Force command post requirements.
You think it's at Yellow Stone Ridge?
Can you be sure?
Without on-site reconnaissance,
I can't make a final judgment.
We need to go take a look.
Just in case my speculation is right,
if we miss this opportunity
and choose the wrong target to strike,
it's highly likely that we
will lose this battle.
But Guo Zijian,
do you know what time it is?
You're the main attack Battalion Commander.
The 1st Battalion's combat mission
cannot afford any delays.
You want to go to Yellow Stone Ridge now?
Are you kidding me?
Political Commissar.
I can't go.
But someone can.
Battalion Commander Guo.
Our reconnaissance detachment
is assigned to the 396th Brigade.
We only answer to the brigade leaders.
Besides,
since you felt our recon results
were just armchair strategy,
why bother with this unnecessary move?
I was wrong.
I apologize to you.
You are not armchair strategists.
You are scientific elites.
Comrade Zeng Muhan.
I'll have to trouble you
to make the trip.
Yes, sir.
Once you reach the reconnaissance area,
please contact me on a dedicated line.
Yes, sir.
Hurry back to the 1st Battalion.
Recon detachment, attention!
Grab your gear.
Move out immediately!
Yes, sir!
Battalion Commander.
Was everything we did tonight
all for nothing?
What do you mean, for nothing?
The group army's recon detachment
have already moved out, right?
Is Zeng Muhan up to it?
After all, West Wind Valley
was the target they gave us.
All we can do now
is head back and make
full preparations for an attack.
If the target changes,
we'll be ready to respond.
Yes, sir.
In a tiny place like this,
setting up camp for the command center
must be a downgrade for you, Commander.
As long as we can win the battle,
even a toilet-sized space will do.
Keep the Laohukou backup command post?
Did I say it was a backup?
A so-called command center
is just some command equipment,
a group of staff officers,
and a bunch of support personnel.
Wherever I, Long Yuanshan, am,
is the command center.
Battalion Commander.
Is that true?
Inside intel.
Absolutely reliable.
A leopard can't change its spots.
At a time like this,
Guo Zijian is still trying to show off?
Yeah.
I heard that
if the Political Commissar wasn't there,
Deputy Brigade Commander Suo wanted to
sack him on the spot.
No.
Get Xu Dali here.
Yes, sir.
Map.
Deputy Brigade Commander.
What's the rush?
Guo Zijian just
reported a new situation.
He led men to reconnoiter
the Blue Force command post again.
He found that this command post
is very likely a fake.
The command post is a core stronghold.
We sent two recon teams,
and both returned unscathed,
yet reached different conclusions.
This
is indeed quite abnormal.
Although Guo Zijian is a bit unreliable,
at this critical juncture,
he wouldn't just talk nonsense.
Then what do you think we should do?
Have the 3rd and 4th Battalions,
and most of the Firepower Battalion,
assemble along the Shigun River.
Prepare
to strike Jade Emperor Peak.
The 2nd Battalion will mobilize,
and the reserve forces
will stand by.
But based on the current situation,
Jade Emperor Peak is very likely
a decoy set by the Blue Force
to distract us.
The reason they're playing these tricks
is actually to figure out
our troop deployment.
We can
use their trick against them.
Concentrate our firepower
and take Jade Emperor Peak
to score the first point.
Then occupy favorable terrain,
take the initiative,
and move the fight to Jade Emperor Peak.
This way,
we can advance or retreat.
It will be much easier
to wipe out the enemy's main force later.
Report to Political Commissar Kang?
I'll brief him personally later.
Hurry up and deploy the troops.
Yes, sir.
What about the 1st Battalion?
They'll act according to the original plan.
I know what you want to say.
But think about it,
the 1st Battalion is our
main attack battalion.
Only by striking the target as planned
can we confuse Long Yuanshan.
Understand?
That's our main attack battalion's role.
Report!
Xu Dali, come here.
Your orders, Battalion Commander?
Once the battle begins,
leave your original standby area,
and move towards the brigade command post.
Why?
Don't ask why.
Take your attached firepower.
I'll assign the brigade's long-range fire
assigned to you as well.
But they have their own defense forces.
Xu Dali.
Ensuring the brigade command post's safety
is our battalion's mission anyway.
Understood?
Understood.
I'll go arrange it right now.
This Guo Zijian is going too far.
He's just a Battalion Commander.
A petty little officer.
Calling our recon unit worthless.
Why should we listen to him?
This mission
was given by the Political Commissar
personally.
Isn't it all the same?
That's enough.
All we need to do
is obey orders
and complete the mission.
Yes.
The Battalion Commander is worried about
Long Yuanshan's decapitation tactic.
The decapitation tactic
has always been Long Yuanshan's style.
Though that kid Guo Zijian acts crazy,
maybe
he really did discover something.
We have to keep something in reserve
just in case.
Report!
Battalion Commander!
There's an adjustment to our combat plan.
Speak.
Our main firepower
will strike Jade Emperor Peak.
Our 1st Battalion
will continue to strike the original target.
Then they...
What exactly does this mean?
They only half-believe my conclusion,
so they chose the safest approach.
Any news from Zeng Muhan?
Reporting, Battalion Commander.
We haven't received any signals from the
reconnaissance unit.
At this time,
panicking won't solve the problem.
Let's patiently wait a bit longer.
They realized the target was incorrect.
Then why mobilize the main force
towards Jade Emperor Peak?
Fools!
Sir, please calm down.
Don't you always say
that exercises are about finding problems?
That the more problems exposed,
the deeper the lessons learned?
Haven't we seen enough of this?
How many units have learned their lesson?
If things keep going like this,
we'll have to change the exercise rules.
But, sir,
these are just small-scale skirmishes.
The real show
is yet to come.
Right?
Zijian.
It'll be dawn soon.
Our battalion is firing
the first shot of the brigade's offensive.
You don't need to remind me of that.
I know the weight of this shot.
Up until now,
there's been no news from Zeng Muhan.
At a time like this,
we absolutely cannot
change the operational plan on our own.
The brigade command post just sent someone.
Time and time again,
they say we must obey discipline.
Emphasizing discipline at this juncture...
It's aimed right at me, Guo Zijian.
Don't I know that?
As soldiers,
aren't we supposed to obey orders?
Fine, we'll do it your way.
Guo Zijian.
Inside that head of yours,
what scheme are you cooking up now?
You shouldn't have agreed so quickly.
The faster you agree,
the more worried I get.
Use the multi-function recon device
to observe the woods 300 meters ahead.
We're not waiting anymore.
Notify Wu Dongsheng
to come to the command post immediately.
Yes, sir.
Wu Dongsheng and the entire recon squad
are standing by.
Worthy of our 1st Battalion recon leader.
The battle is about to start,
but we still haven't received
any news from the army group's recon unit.
Your mission is
to scout the Yellow Stone Ridge area.
We will accomplish the mission!
Wu Dongsheng,
wait a moment.
I need to discuss this with the Commander.
The window of opportunity is fleeting.
There's no time to discuss.
Wu Dongsheng.
Yes, sir!
Step outside.
I know
you're worried about Yellow Stone Ridge.
But the main assault is about to begin.
We can't afford any mistakes right now.
The army group sent out their recon unit.
Even in the worst case,
even if something goes wrong
and delays the battle,
it has nothing to do with you, Guo Zijian.
I don't like the sound of that.
I never just settle for avoiding blame.
I want to win the battle.
If a commander has doubts about a target,
shouldn't they conduct reconnaissance?
I understand your intentions are good.
But doing this...
Fine, fine, fine.
I can never win an argument with you.
Just let me have this one, okay?
If anything happens,
I, Guo Zijian, will take responsibility.
I won't drag you down.
What do you mean you won't drag me down?
We're already in the same boat.
If things go wrong, we share the blame.
Alright.
Wu Dongsheng.
Yes, sir!
Move out!
Yes, sir.
It's over
What's wrong?
We've been ambushed.
Freeze!
Don't move!
Looks like Guo Zijian was right.
I'll hold them off for a while.
Hurry up and transmit the coordinates!
Alright.
Stop whispering.
None of you are getting away.
You talk big.
How would we know without a fight?
Anyone trying to run
will be shot dead.
Anyone wanting to fight,
we'll fight you to the end.
Count off!
One!
Two!
Three!
Four!
Five!
Six!
Seven!
All present!
Huzi!
Here!
Shaolong!
Shunzi!
Here!
Switch to the Liebao for disguised recon.
Yes, Sir!
Squad Leader,
They're all my own.
You can't play favorites.
Squad Leader,
let everyone go.
Even a hero needs helpers.
Stop pushing your luck.
The rest of you,
hurry back and get some sleep.
Squad Leader, take me with you.
You'll need a tough fighter anyway, right?
That's enough.
Didn't you hear the Squad Leader?
Scouts need to use their brains.
Stop talking about fighting all the time.
Wu Dongsheng!
Political Instructor.
It's dark and the path is treacherous.
Make sure to stay safe.
Yes, Sir!
I'll make sure to be careful.
Awaiting your triumphant return.
I guarantee the mission will be complete!
Nice moves.
Take him away.
Move.
Staff Officer Liang.
Why aren't they in a recon vehicle?
Under special circumstances,
they can use appropriate vehicles
to conduct disguised reconnaissance.
You think tracking a recon team right now
makes us penny wise, pound foolish?
Don't worry.
Their normal offensive operations here
are all going according to plan.
I requested this from Exercise Control.
They will send a recorder over.
When the time comes, they will provide us
with fully detailed footage.
No.
Staff Officer Liang, it's about to start.
What kind of trouble can one recon team
even stir up?
This is what Exercise Control wants.
And this variable
is often the turning point of the battle.
Seriously,
why whenever Guo Zijian is mentioned,
it's about variables and uncertainties?
I also want to see
if Guo Zijian's judgment
can truly
surpass the results of data analysis.
Alright, Staff Officer Liang.
Then hold on tight.
Report.
Go ahead.
Hunting squad reporting.
Captured five Red-beaked Birds.
They sneaked all the way here.
Word didn't get out, right?
We captured them the moment they woke up.
Their equipment wasn't even turned on yet.
Wouldn't Red's recon losing contact
prove that something is going on here?
This area is huge.
They can't pinpoint the exact location,
let alone determine
what kind of troops are actually here.
Indeed.
They don't have much time left.
But for the Red side to think of
West Wind Valley and Yellow Stone Ridge,
and send recon personnel there...
It seems this Suo Jian'an
knows his stuff.
Playing chess against a master
is thrilling.
If Suo Jian'an really were a lousy player,
this battle wouldn't be interesting.
But perhaps
he still has a trick up his sleeve.
Political Commissar,
how could you listen to Guo Zijian?
We can't let emotions dictate a war.
Anyway, Zeng Muhan and his team
don't have any tasks right now.
Letting them make the trip
will at least give us peace of mind.
You're being too protective of Guo Zijian.
Jian'an, you're Acting Brigade Commander.
I understand your pressure as a commander.
But I think
on some crucial issues,
you should handle things calmly.
First of all,
I admit
I'm a bit annoyed with that kid.
But...
But
you care too much about his attitude
instead of his opinions.
Political Commissar, you're my old boss.
I accept your criticism.
I know since the exercise began,
you've been helping me build authority.
But think about it,
a major battle is imminent.
As a commander,
I can't afford to be indecisive.
Besides,
I didn't completely ignore his opinions.
Otherwise,
how could I change the plan last minute?
Section Chief Liu!
Here!
Notify all offensive units.
All units must take battle positions!
Yes, sir!
Battalion Commander
Suo wants to secure Jade Emperor Peak,
but has the 1st Battalion keep its plan.
This sidelines the 1st Battalion.
Notify the drones to search this area.
Guo Zijian's temperament,
does Deputy Brigade Commander Suo not know?
Putting him in his current position
is the most appropriate choice.
Then having us stand by here,
what's the reasoning behind that?
At seven o'clock,
when the 1st Battalion fires first,
we'll know if West Wind Valley is real.
If that kid Guo Zijian actually
guesses right by some dumb luck,
the Blue Army's main force is a mystery.
Deputy Brigade Commander Suo knew this,
so he moved the fight to Jade Emperor Peak.
But once they deploy at Jade Emperor Peak,
the Blue Army will send reinforcements.
When that time comes,
that's when our ace unit
will truly come into play.
So that's why you said
who is the main attack and who assists
isn't decided yet.
Learn from this.
Yes, sir.
Don't worry, Squad Leader.
Except for a few wild pheasants flying by
making ugly clucking noises,
there hasn't been a single sound.
Cut the crap.
Besides,
we already captured all five of their
Red-beaked Birds just now.
I guess right now,
the Red Army command post is complaining
and why they aren't reporting back.
If they don't go back,
it'll draw out their follow-up squads.
Keep your eyes peeled, all of you.
Why do you think the enemy was so sure
and just charged right at us?
I can't explain it in just one sentence.
I get it.
What do you get?
That you don't get it either.
Are you asking for a beating?
Stay alert.
Understood.
Squad Leader.
We're here for reconnaissance.
And we've got a tail following us.
If we get exposed,
it's our 1st Battalion that loses face.
Just keep quiet.
No, I mean,
the Commander asked us to scout this area,
but I don't see traces of the Blue Army.
Would the traces be laid out for you?
Don't we have to look for them?
Shaolong, drive slower.
Got it.
There's an intersection ahead.
There's a small road behind the village.
Squad Leader,
you're really amazing.
I almost missed it.
Your eyesight is incredible.
Quit kissing ass and drive properly.
Everyone, be careful.
There's something unusual about this road.
Stop the car.
Huzi.
Look carefully.
Squad Leader.
The width of the road ahead
is fine for our heavy equipment.
Okay, note it down.
Shunzi, log the coordinates.
Mount up.
Staff Officer Liang.
The road ahead is pretty rough.
Average driving skills won't cut it.
You shouldn't follow us anymore.
Who are you looking down on?
I'm not looking down on anyone.
I'm just looking out for you guys.
If our position gets exposed...
Who takes the blame?
How about...
You guys just wait here.
Maybe our main force will pass by here.
Then you can easily collect your evidence.
Right?
Staff Officer Liang, they're provoking us.
I think he's right.
If we encounter the enemy,
and give away their position...
Who takes the blame?
I don't think we need to follow them.
We should keep an eye on Guo Zijian.
No, I have a feeling...
We won't be disappointed this time.
Let's go. Drive.
Staff Officer Liang.
Then do you trust my driving skills?
Get out. Let me drive.
I've had special tactical driving training.
What are you waiting for? Hurry up.
Otherwise, we'll lose them.
Yes!
I guarantee you on my Party loyalty
that as of right now,
Zeng Muhan hasn't made any contact with us.
Has your communication system...
...been working properly this whole time?
It's working perfectly.
The comms officer has been up all night.
He's been staring at the radio all night.
That area Guo Zijian was suspicious of...
What did he do about it?
Political Commissar,
since he hasn't heard from Zeng Muhan,
Guo Zijian had no choice
but to send the battalion recon squad.
I knew he'd do that.
Any response?
None so far.
The situation is urgent now.
Stop obsessing over that spot.
Yes, sir.
Squad Leader, you guessed right.
They really have reinforcements.
But they're too fast. What do we do?
Orders from the command post.
Let these scouts in.
Take them all prisoner.
Once they enter Second Slope,
they'll reach our command post.
What are you afraid of?
As soon as they enter the trap,
we'll box them in and take them down.
Listen up, everyone.
Get ready for combat.
Something's not right.
Should we signal the Battalion Commander?
Send what signal?
Do you even know their positions?
Their troop numbers or equipment?
You know nothing, so what would you send?
Understood.
If we misjudge the situation,
and mislead them, then what?
Then what do we do, Squad Leader?
What do we do?
Huzi, no matter what happens,
you and Shunzi just keep taking notes.
Yes, sir.
But in this kind of terrain,
I'm afraid...
Afraid of what?
Even if you can't use a pen,
you have to cross-check using your brains
and memorize it firmly.
Yes, sir.
Staff Officer Liang, why did we stop?
The Blue Force wants to take prisoners.
Let's not get in their way.
So this is the Blue Force's command post.
We don't know yet.
Wu Dongsheng's team spotted it too.
Hold on tight.
Switch the lens to wide-angle.
Close-quarters combat is about to start.
Pay attention. Don't miss any details.
Don't worry, Staff Officer Liang.
I'm the base's info-gathering champion.
Synchronize watches.
Combat time:
June 6, 2017.
06:40.
Roll call!
1st Battalion, Guo Zijian!
Here!
2nd Battalion, Jiang Shengqiang!
What's the deal with this road?
The Blue Force probably set it up.
To obstruct enemy vehicles,
so they can't operate effectively inside.
No wonder they're the Crash Brigade.
They'll make Wu Dongsheng's team crash.
Squad Leader.
We're sneaking into the Blue Force's base?
Isn't that perfect?
Aren't we looking for their base?
Huzi.
I'll say this one last time.
Record the battlefield elements.
The key is the coordinates.
If you miss anything and mess things up,
I'll rip your head off and kick it.
Yes, Squad Leader.
Squad Leader, there's a roadblock ahead.
Turn left, straight into Second Slope.
Let me drive.
What?
Let me drive. You can't outdrive him.
Hurry!
Today, I'm going to see for myself
just what the hell this Second Slope
is actually hiding.
Still no news from Wu Dongsheng?
Sir, not yet.
Signalman!
Sir!
Get me Li Songwei from the 1st Company.
Yes, sir.
Copy that.
Prepare to attack Yellow Stone Ridge.
Once the order is received,
we move out immediately.
Yes, sir.
Staff Officer Liang,
we're here to gather information,
not to pursue them.
The woods are so dense.
If we don't follow closely,
you'll only end up filming leaves.
Squad leader, we lost them.
That driving was awesome.
I didn't expect Red to have such a pro.
Squad leader, are you okay?
Shut up.
Huzi, you guys go check the perimeter.
Besides the tents,
see if there are any equipment markings.
Reporting, Squad Leader!
Tanks spotted ahead.
Comms vehicles, command vehicles.
All standard issue for a command post.
Squad Leader, we did it!
Beautiful!
Mission accomplished.
Send the coordinates immediately.
Squad Leader, watch out!
It's just an exercise.
Is there a need to be so terrified?
Let's see where you can run.
Remember these points.
First.
The Blue Army will likely encircle us.
Their route of encirclement
is exactly the route we just took.
Second.
On both sides of the route,
they have heavy and jamming equipment.
Third.
I suspect the Blue Army's command post
is located right in Second Slope.
Do you see the bushes behind us
at our eight o'clock?
I'll drive over there in a moment.
You'll use the cover of the bushes
to jump out.
I'll drive on and lure them away.
Scatter as soon as you hit the ground.
Report to the Battalion Commander,
then wait for rescue.
Squad Leader, what about you?
I'll probably spend
the night at the Blue Army's camp.
But as long as the mission is complete,
being captured will be worth it.
Remember, the coordinates and intel
must be sent back no matter what.
Why is Wu Dongsheng's team circling back?
He must be looking for a new way out.
There's no way out.
The Blue Army's ground forces closed in.
Squad Leader, it's Long Yuanshan!
Jump!
Squad Leader Hong,
Secure the scene. I'll track them.
Yes, sir.
Get out and save them!
Save them!
Remember,
send the info back no matter what.
Exercise Control, Exercise Control.
This is Liang Hong.
There's been an accident here.
We have injuries.
Please send a rescue convoy immediately,
along with military medics.
Our location is
the Blue Force position at Second Slope.
Reporting, Battalion Commander.
All combat units are completely ready.
Will the suppressive fire launch on time?
Reporting, Battalion Commander.
Received coordinates from the scout squad.
Second Slope at Yellow Stone Ridge
is the Blue Force's command center.
Beautiful!
Good.
Old Guo, there is less than a minute
before the main attack is launched.
There's no time to adjust,
let alone report to superiors.
Tell me, what should we do?
Then we execute Plan B.
Deputy Battalion Commander!
Here!
Order immediately,
all our battalion's long-range firepower,
except 2nd Company's support forces,
to change trajectory and coordinates,
and on the Yellow Stone Ridge area,
launch a saturation strike!
At the same time, the 1st Armored Company,
the 1st and 3rd Infantry Companies,
the engineering and demolition units,
along with all assigned
fire support from the Theater Army,
will all deploy
and assault Yellow Stone Ridge!
Yes!
Also,
have 1st Company flank Yellow Stone Ridge
and mop up their remaining forces.
Yes!
Staff Officer Hu!
Here!
Draft a combat adjustment request at once.
Yes!
The content is as follows.
Our battalion, at 06:59 this morning,
acquired accurate information,
locating the Blue Force command post
and their main forces' assembly area,
with coordinates and force deployment.
To achieve maximum combat effectiveness,
our battalion has adjusted its main forces
to strike the enemy at Yellow Stone Ridge.
Please handle accordingly,
and adjust the combat plan.
396th Brigade 1st Battalion Commander Guo.
Arrogant, simply arrogant!
If everyone acted like this,
what's the point of having commanders?
True, his actions are inappropriate.
But Old Suo, as commander-in-chief,
you absolutely cannot lose your cool.
How can I not lose it, Political Commissar?
Is this how things are done?
The general offensive was about to start,
and he changed the combat direction!
Is this a joke? Child's play?
Old Suo, I have verified it.
The 1st Battalion was one minute away
when they received the information.
They submitted the request immediately.
A request?
Time was tight, so it's excusable.
What does a request mean?
It means asking for a superior's consent.
Did you approve it? Did I approve it?
Oh, so he just goes his own way.
No sense of organization or discipline!
Yes.
You're right.
Under such circumstances,
as Party Committee Secretary,
I bear direct responsibility.
At first, I also felt
Guo Zijian's judgment wasn't unreasonable.
However, his main attack direction
was changed by you to a probing strike.
So wouldn't striking
Yellow Stone Ridge, with accurate info,
be more effective?
The problem is,
we can't verify the info on the ridge now.
What if it's another Blue Force trick?
He'd not only be wasting firepower,
he might also expose our position!
Alright, let's stop arguing.
The strike results will be out soon.
Let's wait and see.